Melissa Ortíz R.

UX-UT DESTGNER

Enthusiastic multidisciplinary designer with 2+ years of architecture & design experience. My passion is creating exceptional experiences in digital products and designing intuitive, enjoyable solutions throughout the user journey.

My architecture background has given me a unique perspective as a designer. Creative thinking, user-centered design and technical skills, are the common denominators I share in both of my career paths.

I am a never-ending learner who enjoys solving complex problems.

WANT TO KNOW MORE ABOUT ME?







+57 302 207 0763

Click HERE to see my portfolio

Experience

April 2022 - Present

Architectural lead designer

GonSAS Company

- Successfully **led multiple architectural design projects** from to proposal to completion, ensuring adherence to timelines and budgets.
- Led the user research process to design spaces with a **harmonious balance between form and practical function** to enhance the user interaction and experience within the environment, starting with a **deep understanding of the user needs** and how they will feel within the space.
- Led the design team into **winning six proposals** of high-level contracts with multiple universities in Bogota, summing up **1.5 MM USD** in valuation.

September 2021 - March 2022

Architectural Designer

Kodama Company

- Led the design process for **50 high-profile residential** eco-friendly houses, each one with multiple customizations in style, interior design and materials.
- Applied a **design thinking** approach to develop spaces that enhanced user experience, functionality and sustainability.
- Leveraged 3D modeling and design software to create intuitive visualizations of designs for customers.
- Refined designs according to client's input, ensuring the final outcome met all requirements, specification and budget.

Diciembre 2019 - Mayo 2021

Intern

Urbanittá

- Developed urban design proposals, employing innovative solutions for the **revitalization** and utility of space.
- Analyzed social behaviors, mobility patterns and urbanistic zone distributions to find the most functional configurations for local inhabitants.

Independent Projects and Apps

WFB-APP GAME

- The website features **six characters**, each designed with a thoughtfully selected color palette and typography to enhance user engagement.
- The game focuses on having two characters confront each other, each with their own powers, and managing their lives to determine a winner.
- Web-app developed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

FOOD MARKET APP 🚡

- The application aimed to create a recipe app connected to a supermarket to ensure product delivery, cost estimation, and recipe guidance.
- App designed using Figma, Illustrator and Photoshop.

QUICKNOTES APP &



Education

2017 -2021

Universidad de La Salle

Bachelor Degree in Architecture Design GPA: 4.3/5.0

Platzi

User Centered Design User Research Advanced Figma Design Sprint Mobile Interface Design Design Thinking

Awards and Recognitions

2021

Universidad de La Salle

Meritorious Research Award Nominee

<u> 2021</u>

Urbanittá

Finalist Alma Viva Contest

<u> 2020</u>

ACFA

Finalist Ciudades y arquitecturas abiertas

SKILLS

UX - UI tools

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD

Visual Design

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign.

Design Methods

Wireframing, typography, interface design, User research, Design thinking.

Prototyping

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.